Prakash Parmar

Front-End Developer

Phone:

8866808798

Address

Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India

Website :

https://pekskumar.github.io/Has-Websites/ [HTML, CSS, jQuery] https://pekskumar.github.io/Has-Websites-Reactjs-js/ (React Library)

Email:

prakash.montu 92@live.com

*PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I've been working from 1.6+ year as a Frontend Developer. During that time I've been trained software platforms and systems. I have experience in React js, WordPress, HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Jquery, Javascript and Bootstrap. I am Passionate about implementing and launching new projects. Looking to start the career as Full-Stack Frontend Developer with a reputed firm driven by technology.

* EXPERIENCES

April, 2022 -Present

Front-End Engineer

Acquaint Softtech Private Limited

- Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement
- Design web applications according to client briefs and modify designs to meet changes in client specifications
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using React js, HTML5, SAAS, CSS3, jQuery and Javascript.
- Collaborated with web designers, back end developers and UX designers to design, build, test and improve web products
- Ensured scalability of front end elements by optimizing them for loading speed and performance
- Assisted in the training of new developers and web designers
- Designing the Web Application using HTML5, SCSS , Bootstrap , jQuery with WordPress, Angular and Laravel.
- Ensure efficient web development by supporting designers and app developers while resolving website performance issues

February, 2021 - April, 2022

Front-End Developer

CodeCaste Pvt Ltd

- Experience themes and builder in WordPress such as Avada, Elementor, DIVI, Visual Composer, Astra, Sydney and WPBakery etc.
- Developing customizing website using CBD in WordPress
- Experience in Web Application Development in React js Environment
- Designing fully customizing and pixel-perfect responsive website using Media Query and designing mobile-based features
- Ability to write Effectively, clean, minimalistic, reusable code
- Utilized Adobe Photoshop, XD and Figma for the production of web-optimized Images
- Experience in Front-end coding and deployment in a JavaScript Environment
- Understood the marketing objectives for each project assigned and ensured deadlines for assigned projects were met
- Maintained accuracy and attention to detail throughout the creative and

development process.

- Handled multiple projects simultaneously while ensuring all projects were completed within the deadline date.
- Worked collaboratively with developers and in-house team to develop and maintain websites for a variety of clients.

June 2016 -October 2020

ST. XAVIER'S HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Computer Assistant Teacher

- Organize, maintain and manage class systems in proper working condition.
- Prepare execute lesson plans, assigning tasks, and evaluating student work and progress.
- Design and develop appropriate computer instructional material.
- Manage and monitor student behavior. Conduct group training sessions.
- Creating inventory and report files for computer Lab as monthly basis
- Designing and developing website for school and everyday updation and also handling google business account
- Doing office work like Aadhaar Enabled DISE online application form filling and making Students General Register book
- Making question paper for all subjects like Gujarati, Hindi, Sanskrit and English Languages
- Updating computer software programs and hardware components as needed.
- Install computer software programs and computer hardware and accessories.

* TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend Js Libraries

(Reacls)

- React Router
- React Component
- JSX
- Node + NPM
- Virtual DOM
- Ison
- Hooks
- map()
- Material UI
- AXIOS
- Redux-Saga(Basic)

Frontend Languages, etc.

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS(CSS)
- BOOTSTRAP
- jQuery
- XD
- Figma
- Git
- Angular
- PHOTOSHOP

- Ajax
- Javascript

PHP CMS (WordPress)

- Theme Integration
- WordPress Plugins Integrate
- HTML Customization
- contact form7
- · Gravity Forms
- WP File Manager
- Themes & Builder Avada, elementor, Divi, wpbakery, etc.

* SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- Web Development
- Cross Browser Operability
- Project management
- Process Improvement
- Workflow Optimization
- User Requirements Gathering

* GOOGLE EXTENSIONS

- PerfectPixel
- Width and Height Display
- React Developer Tools
- SetupVPN
- Lightshot
- Screencastify Screen Video Recorder
- Nimbus

* PROJECTS

https://pekskumar.github.io/Has-Websites/

https://pekskumar.github.io/Has-Websites-Reactjs-js/ Live Demo (Using React Js Library)

* SOCIAL ACCOUNT

Linked in

linkedin.com/in/pek-s-kumar-ba2636125

GitHub

https://github.com/Pekskumar

* EDUCATION

MCA [SEM-5]

L.J. Institute of Computer Applications(GTU)

BCA

St. Xavier's college(GU)

D.El.Ed.

NIOS (Govt. of India)

* CERTIFICATES

PHP (TOPS Technologies)

DCA [Shree Sahjanand Computer Center]

Tally 9 [Soni Academy Computer Training & Computer Education]

* AWARDS

Good Academic Grades Award

St. Xavier's College, Ahmedabad

* LANGUAGES

English

,

Gujarati

Hindi

* HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Programming
- Travelling
- Designing
- Internet surfing
- Cricket
- Painting
- Reading books

* DECLARATION

I hereby certify that all the information provided here is correct to the best of my knowledge.